<?xml version="1.0"?>

<vowel ref="8" name="e">
<title>Sin</title>
<image>e.jpg</image>
<pronunciation>/e/ like the 'e' in 'men'
</pronunciation>
<w id="1">
<d>(a) not innocent person
</d>
</w>

<w id="2">
<d>[found]
</d>
</w>

<w id="3">
<d>(owned by) another person's [owner/baker]
</d>
</w>

<w id="4">
<d>[bread]/[bread oven] [goods]
</d>
</w>

<w id="5">
<d>[brought it] [fled to]
</d>
</w>

<w id="6">
<d>[obfuscating] [dirty] city
</d> 
</w>

<w id="7">
<d>distributing
</d>
</w>

<w id="8">
<d>excepting (the baker) [lacking]
</d>
</w>

<w id="9">
<d>(to the) [masses]
</d>
</w>

<w id="10">
<d>(it) spread [both good (7) and bad (9)]
</d>
</w>

<w id="11">
<d>apparent beauty
</d>
</w>

<w id="12">
<d>(there was) existed [gibt es] [reflexive of a kind]
</d>
</w>

<w id="13">
<d>joker
</d>
</w>

<w id="14">
<d>[smoked]/laughed/mesmerized
</d>
</w>

<w id="15">
<d>production [stopped]
</d>
</w>

<w id="16">
<d>famous (thief)
</d>
</w>

<w id="17">
<d>[returned] [walked aimlessly, serendipitously]
</d>
</w>

<w id="18">
<d>suddenly [witnessed]
</d>
</w>

<w id="19">
<d>said/implored "let me give (to you)
</d>
</w>

<w id="20">
<d>(with) plenty"
</d>
</w>

<w id="21">
<d>(baker) replied
</d>
</w>

<w id="22">
<d>(I've been) waiting [too long]
</d>
</w>

<w id="23">
<d>Where/What have you been/done
</d>
</w>

<w id="24">
<d>died unjustly and unloved
</d>
</w>

<w id="25">
<d>(thief) laughed [at the folly]
</d>
</w>

<w id="26">
<d>soliloquoying (to itself)
</d>
</w>

<w id="27">
<d>what could I have done?
</d>
</w>

<translation>
<s refid="1">In the country, traveled a thief--someone that was not innocent.</s><s refid="2">
The thief found </s><s refid="3">a baker's </s><s refid="4">bread, and finding it delicious, stole the baker's
oven.  </s><s refid="5">Fleeing, the thief brought it to </s><s refid="6">the filthy city </s><s refid="7">and began
distribution of the baker's wondrous bread.</s><s refid="8">

Excepting the baker,</s><s refid="9"> the masses loved the bread, </s><s refid="10">and its effects spread through the area </s><s refid="11">providing a healthy glean to the population's faces but there was also disruption.</s><s refid="12">

Now, there existed </s><s refid="13">
a joker, </s><s refid="14">who entertained those that waited on the long lines for the thief's bread.  They would laugh, mezmerized by his performance.  Smoke billowed out from the joker's magic, obscuring the baker who had now turned beggar from the front of the line.
</s><s refid="15">
One day, bread production stopped, and the thief,</s><s refid="16">now famous, </s><s refid="17">wandered aimlessly out of the bread factory, eventually returning to the old bakery.
</s><s refid="18">
Suddenly, he recognized </s><s refid="19">the baker, and rushed up
imploring, "Let me share with you </s><s refid="20">my plenty."
</s><s refid="21">
The baker replied,
</s><s refid="22">
"I've been waiting too long.
</s><s refid="23">
Where have you been?"
</s><s refid="24">
The baker died tragically then, unjustly and unloved.
</s><s refid="25">
At that, the thief laughed sadly,
</s><s refid="26">
soliloquoying,
</s><s refid="27">
"After all, what could I have done?"
</s>
</translation>


<history>

<p>This story was originally entitled 'prodigal son,' and then 'sin.' On the very first notes
page, I have, "poetic justice, "innocent when you dream", web of coincidences, love, hope, --[good intentions], human need and sacrifice, drama, righteousness of liberty, see what is not there (sunglasses), how it affects the stranger
<br />
pride(2), fear(6), greed(5), jealousy(7), glutony(4), deceit, anger(1), sloth, lust(3), obstinence"
</p>
<p>
12/7/99 or 12/8/99: sin (bad english translation)
<br />
One man (not so innocent) "found" a bit of something that was incredibly good but owned (made?) by another man who needed [it] desperately. The first stole it and brought it into the dark [night] (city) streets and distributed the benefits of it to the masses.  All of them he saw in the night because that is where they were.  All, that is, except for the "baker" (i.e. the victim) who had become penniless and destitute and desperate.  The good of the distribution continued to spread and the man/thief became famous. [a third man (helped) the thief "miss" (the baker)].  With the baker destitute.  He could not make [bread] and so many went hungry.  Finally the thief [walked into the day] and suddenly saw (the baker) (and figured out what must have happened) and he said "Here let me give you this bread--(I) have plenty" The baker replied "I've been waiting so long--where have you been?" but then died there unjustly and unloved. The thief, the fool--laughed at the sorrow--"What could I have done?" he asked himself?"
<br />(the above text was minimized into 27 key words that would constitute the story)
<br />the following notes are on the opposing page: "note theme of take from one for the many--the good of the many outweigh good of the one=sin
<br />Dylan: if you're dreaming you're stil sleeping
<br />no Watchmaker in the town
<br />There are other characters in the story.  Each word does not just mean what it says--it is the next sylabol that moves the story forward.
<br />5: "greed"  There must be justice/eveness in discussion, argument, gone=>must either play at level of opposition or counter yourself (block your own thrust). Poker metaphor shows that you are keeping all your cards till you need them.
<br />2: ?lust? metaphor is Hansel and Gretel leaving breadcrumbs. worry if you will be the next breadcrumb eaten.
</p>

</history>

</vowel>
