<?xml version="1.0"?>

<vowel ref="2" name="ou">
<title>Volcano</title>
<image>ou.jpg</image>
<pronunciation>/&#248;/ like the 'ou' in 'about' said by a Canadian
</pronunciation>
<w id="1">
<t>m</t>
<d>town/society
</d>
</w>

<w id="2">
<t>'</t>
<d>just inside (mountains)
</d>
</w>

<w id="3">
<t>n
</t>
<d>family
</d>
</w>

<w id="4">
<t>q
</t>
<d>children
</d>
</w>

<w id="5">
<t>z
</t>
<d>[plus one]
</d>
</w>

<w id="6">
<t>t
</t>
<d>(first) stays home
</d>
</w>

<w id="7">
<t>sh
</t>
<d>(second) leaves (mountains)
</d>
</w>

<w id="8">
<t>@
</t>
<d>(third) searches
</d>
</w>

<w id="9">
<t>f
</t>
<d>guide
</d>
</w>

<w id="10">
<t>w
</t>
<d>settled couple
</d>
</w>

<w id="11">
<t>k
</t>
<d>old-person
</d>
</w>

<w id="12">
<t>s
</t>
<d>followed/aided
</d>
</w>

<w id="13">
<t>th
</t>
<d>expansive view
</d>
</w>

<w id="14">
<t>j
</t>
<d>top,summit
</d>
</w>

<w id="15">
<t>g
</t>
<d>spots, catches sight of
</d>
</w>

<w id="16">
<t>v
</t>
<d>smoke (beacon)
</d>
</w>

<w id="17">
<t>y
</t>
<d>river (depositing, beating down force)
</d>
</w>

<w id="18">
<t>l
</t>
<d>volcano (destructive producing force)
</d>
</w>

<w id="19">
<t>b
</t>
<d>made [sculpted]
</d>
</w>

<w id="20">
<t>r
</t>
<d>(the) mountain range
</d>
</w>

<w id="21">
<t>d
</t>
<d>(the old person) jumps (into the river)
</d>
</w>

<w id="22">
<t>dh
</t>
<d>(third) travels (to volcano)
</d>
</w>

<w id="23">
<t>h
</t>
<d>explosion
</d>
</w>

<w id="24">
<t>p
</t>
<d>burning (third) [directly]
</d>
</w>

<w id="25">
<t>H
</t>
<d>they (town's people, etc: all except second and third)
</d>
</w>

<w id="26">
<t>kh</t>
<d>buried [under]
</d>
</w>

<w id="27">
<t>ng</t>
<d>ash
</d>
</w>

<translation>
  Once upon a time, 
<s refid="1">   there was a village</s><s refid="2">
   just inside a vast mountain range.  The villagers viewed themselves and were viewed by their neighbors as mountain people.  They almost never went deeper into the mountain, but a legend existed inside the village that a volcano was somewhere in the mountains, and that one day it would erupt and destroy the village.
</s><s refid="3">
  There was one family in the village </s><s refid="5">with three </s><s refid="4">children.
  One day, the second eldest child declared that the volcano legend must be fiction, and decided to leave the village
    out of the mountain range.</s><s refid="6">
  The first child stayed home.</s><s refid="7">
  The second child left, as they said they would.</s><s refid="8">
  The third, decided to head into the mountain range
   in search of the volcano.</s><s refid="9">
  After setting off from home into the mountain,
    the first person that the third met was a mountain guide.
  "Where is the volcano?" the third asked the guide.
  The guide did not know where the volcano was, but was
    familiar with a number of paths across the mountain range.
  The third traveled with the guide for some time, learning
    the mountain paths, but eventually decided to go on alone
    knowing that was the only way to find the volcano.
</s><s refid="10">
  Traveling further, the third encountered a settled couple living
    a secluded life inside the mountain range.  They welcomed the child
    into their home, and invited the third to stay.  Staying, the child
    enjoyed a happy routine with the couple, but again decided to set
    off alone on the quest to the volcano.
</s><s refid="11">
  After many more travels, the third encountered an old solitary traveller,
    admitting to looking for the volcano, too.  The old stranger
    believed that a certain peak was the volcano, and
    pointed to it off in the distance.
</s><s refid="12">
  The third child followed the old traveller, and they helped each other towards
    the distant peak.
</s><s refid="13">
  When they arrived, there was an expansive panoramic view 
</s><s refid="14">at the summit, but
    no volcano.  </s><s refid="15">However, in the distance they caught sight of </s><s refid="16">a small tendril of smoke that rose from 
    a peak farther off.</s><s refid="17">
  The old traveller squinted at the smoke and explained that the mountain
    range was created by two forces--pointing to the river far below in the
    ravine, the river created the valleys; </s><s refid="18">and sweeping a hand forward, the
    volcano created the peaks.  </s><s refid="19">Together they sculpted </s><s refid="20">the mountain range.</s><s refid="21">
  With that, the old traveller jumped down into the ravine falling far down
    into the river.</s><s refid="22">
  Alone again, the third child traveled to the volcano's peak.  </s><s refid="23">Reaching the top, the volcano exploded, </s><s refid="24">destroying the child in the
    molten fire.
</s><s refid="25">
  The village's people</s><s refid="26"> were buried </s><s refid="27">under ash.</s>
  
</translation>

<history>
<p>This was the first story that was part of my language, possibly an
inspiration to the project. (That, of course, does not give it any higher
priority, but when making deep critiques of the language and its structure
this may be notable.)  It is also possibly inspired by the story of Pompei and
Pliny the Elder (Pliny the younger's uncle), who died during the volcano's
eruption, and also was known to climb the volcano, interested in geology.
Though I believed it at the time, I'm not sure this corresponds with the
historical record--that Pliny the Elder was in/on top of the volcano studying
it, while it erupted.
</p>
<p>'qou' originally meant "three/plus one (implication being two is a
'natural' number of children)"
</p>
<p>'zou' originally meant "sons" and then meant "children."  'kou' also was
originally gender specific--"old man."  Currently, all words are gender
neutral.  It has been pointed out to me that most (possibly all) folk stories
of a set of children 'going out to adventure' are male.  Does this suggest a
bias in the story, just from this history--(ie is the 'idea' of adventuring in
this way implicitly masculine?)  I have told the story, with all female roles,
and it obviously still makes sense, though perhaps went against the grain of
the audiences I have told it to. The gender neutrality is also possibly
biased, I admit, if everyone reading the story, then assumes or imagines they
are all male characters.  The total gender neutrality also may be simply
unpopular, because we are so raised and accustomed to learning gender roles
through folk tales.
</p>
<p>
On the very first notes page, by volcano, I have, "town, prodigal son, old man,
wrong high mountain, rivers valley, [cave] (points to "settled couple"), sky
family, companion, road/travelled path, explosion, guide, settled couple,"
</p>

</history>

</vowel>
